DANIEL SCHMIDT PINHEIRO

Ottawa, ON | dscpinheiro@gmail.com | https://dscpinheiro.com

SUMMARY

Professional with 5+ years of experience in the IT industry, working primarily with the Microsoft stack (C#, .NET, and ASP.NET MVC). AWS certified, holding all three associate certifications available. Motivated, fast learner, alert to detail, and able to work independently and as part of a team. Strong organization and time management skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

.NET | C# | ASP.NET MVC | ASP.NET Web Api | SQL | Entity Framework | JavaScript | AWS

WORK EXPERIENCE

.NET Developer | Accera | Jan 2015 to Feb 2018 | São Leopoldo, RS, Brazil

- Collaborated in the development of an internal data quality tool used by the customer service team
 to spot and act on problems in the data provided by clients. This tool eliminated many manual
 processes that had to be done daily, and also allowed the company to keep a steady number of
 support employees, even with a considerable growth in the quantity of new customers.
- Migrated multiple parts of an existing legacy application to microservices. By using newer technologies, the time to release new changes reduced dramatically (from once a week to sometimes multiple times a day), and customer satisfaction increased significantly (since some features that weren't technically feasible before, such as responsiveness on mobile devices, became possible).

.NET Developer | Grupo Meta | May 2011 to Dec 2013 | São Leopoldo, RS, Brazil

Developed and maintained several intranet solutions for a Brazilian steel producer. Some of these
included: a document management system used in Mexico, Colombia and other Latin America
countries which helped reduce logistics lead time; and a website to promote a special service, where
customers could have their projects reviewed by specialized engineers.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor's degree in Information Systems | 2012 to 2017 | Unisinos, São Leopoldo, RS, Brazil
- Exchange Student in Computer Science | 2014 | The University of British Columbia | Vancouver, BC
 - Some of the courses taken: Introduction to Relational Databases, Internet Computing, Functional Programming, Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, and Advanced Relational Databases